<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2rc3p3">
<title>CMV:Patriotism is the belief that being born on one side of a line makes you better.</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2rc3p3/cmvpatriotism_is_the_belief_that_being_born_on/</source>
<OP author="sniperman357">
  <claim id="a"> American patriots have a general mentality against immigration. </claim> <relation_support ref="a"> <logos> Saying these people shouldn’t be allowed to become part of the country, is the same as saying they are worse, </logos> <logos> because they were born on a different side of a line </logos>, and <logos> americans are better because of the side of the line they are born on </logos> </relation_support>. <relation_support ref="a"> <logos> This is prominent in many ads and political champagnes, namely the slogan “Creating jobs for americans”. </logos> </relation_support> <claim id="b"> I understand why politics use this slogan </claim>, because <relation_support ref="b"> <logos> they are trying to get americans to vote for them </logos> , but <logos> this slogan is also prominent in ads made by private corporations </logos>. <logos> As if creating jobs for americans is morally superior to creating jobs for people of other countries. </logos> <logos> The companies launching these ads may be trying to win in the american market, so they can sell more of their product, </logos> but <logos> the fact that this can increase sales shows that many americans hold the being born on one side of a line belief </logos> </relation_support> . <claim id="c"> I am not blaming the politicians or corporations running ads running these slogans </claim>, <relation_support ref="c"> <logos> they are merely trying to win votes or make money from this mentality </logos> </relation_support>, but <claim id="d"> really it is the citizens that have the belief that they are better, because of the side of a line they are born on, that are at fault </claim> . <claim> Patriotism is really just this belief. </claim>

_____

&gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*
</OP>
<reply id="cnemor5" author="debatingaccount">
<relation_partial_attack ref="d"> <claim id="e"> I would define patriotism quite simply as supporting one's country, but not *necessarily* disparaging others. </claim> </relation_partial_attack> <relation_support ref="e"> <logos> Therefore I would say that the antithesis of patriotism is not having a global perspective </logos> , but <logos> is in fact selfishness </logos> </relation_support>. <relation_support ref="e"> <logos> <pathos> Someone who attempts to extract gain for themselves at harm to their overall country is acting unpatriotically </pathos> </logos> , <logos> <pathos> someone who assists another country that is in worse shape instead of assisting their own can still be a patriot, but also recognize significant need in other nations and decide to assist them as well </pathos> </logos> </relation_support>. <relation_support ref="e" <logos> <pathos> Whether you support immigration or not, so long as you are supporting what you believe is best for your nation, you are still acting patriotically </pathos> </logos> </relation_support>, and <relation_support ref="e"> <logos> <pathos> even if you decide to support another nation you can still be acting patriotically as well so long as you support your nation too </pathos> </logos> </relation_support>.
</reply>
<reply id="cneqxqg" author="sniperman357">
  <relation_agreement ref="e"> <claim id="f"> This is true </claim> </relation_agreement>, but, <relation_attack ref="e"> <claim id="g"> I think, supporting the common good is also more important than supporting your country </claim> </relation_attack>. 
</reply>
<reply id="cney5lx" author="debatingaccount">
  <relation_agreement ref="g"> <claim id="h"> Yes </claim> </relation_agreement>, but <relation_attack ref="g"> <claim id="i"> the two are often one the same </claim> </relation_attack>, <relation_support ref="i"> <logos> especially when you live in a country as large as the U.S. most acts which serve the common good generally support your country </logos> </relation_support>.
</reply>
</thread>

