<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2qb4ra">
<title>CMV: I think the board game "Monopoly" is poorly designed</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2qb4ra/cmv_i_think_the_board_game_monopoly_is_poorly/</source>
<OP author="Iprefervim">
<relation_support ref="a"> <ethos> Like many American kids, I was often forced throughout my childhood to participate in "Monopoly" games with my family. </ethos> </relation_support> From what I can tell, <claim id="a"> there is very little skill involved in playing the game </claim> , <relation_support ref="a"> <pathos> it just seems to be a giant crapshoot the whole way through </pathos> </relation_support>.

"Monopoly" was made with the intent to explain why localised monopolies are bad for the economy and to explain the Single Tax theory of Henry George.^1 <claim id="b"> Though it does this job well, I believe it is this intent that causes it to be thoroughly not fun. </claim> <relation_support ref="c"> <logos> Once ~50% of the board has been claimed, even if the landholdings of all the players are about equal, it is immediately obvious which player will lose based on who falls in another's territory first and has to pay the incredulous tax. </logos> <logos> After that, it is just a long fall into bankruptcy as eventually the player has to sell their property to others, decreasing the chance that they can earn revenue while simultaneously increasing the chance that the others can profit from them. </logos> </relation_support>

<claim id="c"> While this system would work in a **quick** game between 2 to 3 people, monopoly is usually drawn out and played with 4+ players. </claim> <relation_support ref="c"> <logos> One after another, a player pays out the net-worth to the other players until there is a long, long drawn-out stand-off between the remaining few. </logos> <logos> At this point, it comes to down to complete and utter chance. </logos> <logos> Whomever gets the worst successive dice rolls loses. </logos> <logos> When that happens, barring any statistically unlikely dice rolls, it is evident who will lose. </logos> <logos> But the game keeps going and going, because it would be "unfair" to keep going despite the likely outcome. </logos> </relation_support>

<claim id="d"> If Monopoly was redesigned to rely less on chance (<relation_support id="d"> <logos> perhaps a redesign of the board </logos>, <logos> more mechanics to tip the scales of chance perhaps with better "Chance" cards </logos>, or <logos> even removal of the pieces entirely </logos> </relation_support>) and to be quicker (<relation_support id="d"> <logos> Add penalties for each additional player over 3 so that the success and failures of each decision weigh more heavily </logos> </relation_support>, for example) then the game will be much more fun and enjoyable to everyone. </claim> <relation_support ref="d"> <logos> As of right now, after the first few passes around the board, it is easier to calculate the theoretical outcome with the help of a computer then to finish the game to its completion. </logos> </relation_support>

Please change my view, for the sake of family game night. 

&amp;nbsp;
&gt;^1 Orbanes, Philip E. (2006). Monopoly: The World's Most Famous Game &amp; How it Got that Way. Da Capo Press. p. 22. ISBN 0-306-81489-7.
</OP>
<reply id="cn4iftv" author="skulder7">
  First, are you actually playing monopoly according to the base rules? <claim id="e"> I have to ask </claim> <relation_support ref="e"> <logos> because it's very, very common for people to unwitting ignore or add rules and cause the game to run longer </logos> </relation_support>. <relation_support ref="e"> <logos> By far the most egregious violation of this nature is ignoring the Auction rule (<logos> where if the player who lands on an unbought space chooses not to buy it for face value, it is auctioned off to highest bidder </logos>), which makes it take much longer for people to build up property, dragging out the early stages of the game. </logos> </relation_support> <relation_support id="e"> <logos> Another common one <ethos> I grew up with </ethos> was the "Free Parking" rule addition, <logos> where landing on Free Parking confers some kind of monetary reward </logos>, which introduces more money into the game and makes it harder to go bankrupt, dragging out the game. </logos> </relation_support>

<claim id="f"> Assuming that you're playing with auctions (and preferably without that Free Parking house rule), the key to the game is negotiation. </claim> <relation_support ref="f"> <logos> The game only becomes a drawn-out slugfest if players can't get monopolies </logos>, <logos> which only happens if players don't negotiate </logos> </relation_support> . <relation_support ref="f"> <pathos> This is the soul of the game </pathos>, and <logos> <pathos>  ignoring it is the reason many people develop a distaste for the game </pathos> </logos> </relation_support> . <relation_support ref="f"> <pathos>  If players A, B, C, and D are playing, and A is obviously ahead after a few go-arounds, should A just win? </pathos> <pathos> Of course not! B, C, and D should be conspiring like hell to take A down. </pathos> <logos>B can "not notice" when C and D land on his properties, making A the only one to pay rent. </logos> <logos> C and D can agree to help each other complete monopolies and make trades of that nature. </logos> <logos> Once some players have monopolies, the other players have to either trade to make their own monopolies or get bled out quickly. </logos> <logos> Once monopolies (and the corresponding houses and hotels) come into play, tiny rents become enormous and the game quickly comes to an end. </logos> </relation_support>

In short, <claim id="g"> Monopoly is drawn out because people don't play by the rules, or the miss the main point of the game : monopolies </claim>. <relation_support ref="g"> <logos> Forming monopolies is by far the quickest way to win </logos> , and <logos> the easiest way to do so is through negotiating with other players, a point that many Monopoly players fail to notice </logos> </relation_support> . <relation_support ref="g"> <logos> A properly played game of Monopoly may come down to luck in the end </logos> , but <logos> it's luck that is heavily influenced by the mid-game, which is decided by the players' diplomatic skill </logos> </relation_support> . 
</reply>
<reply id="cn4jvja" author="Iprefervim">
<relation_agreement ref="g"> <claim id="h"> That is a possibility of have not considered actually </claim> </relation_agreement> . <relation_support ref="h"> <ethos> Only recently (past 4 years) my family added money to the free parking </ethos> , and <ethos> though I always attempted to get the auction rule in I was always voted down </ethos> </relation_support> . <relation_partial_agreement ref="g"> <claim id="i"> Perhaps that is the reason why I have such a strong dislike of the game. </claim> </relation_partial_agreement> Alas, I have not actually played it in a while and I'll play it with these rules before confirming the delta, for these rules may not be enough to convince me that the game is designed well. <relation_partial_agreement ref="g"> <claim id="i"> Though it is theoretically sound it may not hold up </claim> </relation_partial_agreement>
</reply>
<reply id="cn4kqwf" author="skulder7">
  <relation_agreement ref="i"> <claim id="j"> It does admittedly depend a lot on the people you play it with. </claim> </relation_agreement> <relation_support ref="j"> <logos> <pathos> If your fellow players absolutely refuse to negotiate, even when it would benefit them in the long run, then the game is not going to be fun. </pathos> </logos> <logos> It's like playing poker with players who never bet </logos> : <pathos> it's not fun, it's just a long, awful slog </pathos> </relation_support> . <claim id="k"> That doesn't make Poker a bad game by design </claim> (<relation_support ref="k"> <logos> <pathos> even though it can be unfun in some scenarios </pathos> </logos> </relation_support>); <relation_support ref="k"> <logos> <pathos>it just means that it's not a game that everyone will enjoy </pathos> </logos> </relation_support> . 

  <claim id="l"> I'd recommend pointing out to people that the point of the game is to make trades. </claim> <relation_support ref="l"> <ethos> <logos> The most beneficial trade I've found involves two players helping each other complete a monopoly, but giving "immunity" to that group. </logos> </ethos> (<logos> i.e. Alice has two Yellow properties and one Green property, while Bob has two Green properties and one Yellow property </logos> . <logos> Alice agrees to trade her Green for Bob's Yellow, giving them both monopolies, on the condition that Alice won't have to pay if she lands on a Green property and Bob won't have to pay if he lands on a Yellow property </logos>). </relation_support> <relation_support ref="l"> <pathos> <logos> Players who don't like trades tend to be nervous about giving other players a better position </logos> </pathos>, and <ethos> <logos> <pathos> I find that they're more inclined to do so if they feel it won't come back to bite them </pathos> </logos> </ethos>. <pathos> Seriously, immunity is great </pathos> </relation_support> . <relation_support ref="l"> <logos> Even without auctions, making sure people are aware that they can be "flexible" about collecting rent makes the game go much faster. </logos> <logos> If you can't sell auctions, this should still help. </logos> </relation_support>
</reply>
<reply id="cn4le0e" author="Iprefervim">
∆

  <relation_agreement ref="l"> <claim id="m"> Yeah, you're right. </claim> </relation_agreement> <relation_support ref="l"> <ethos> <logos> Perhaps my family (and quite a few other families) are just not equipped to play this game. </logos> </ethos> </relation_support> <relation_support ref="m"> <logos> It is probably akin to Diplomacy </logos>: <logos> The family dynamic + the individual personalities of each player changes how the game goes </logos> </relation_support> . Thanks for the brilliant and well thought out answer.
</reply>
</thread>
