<?xml version="1.0"?>
<thread ID="2qaf6l">
<title>CMV: If a child struggles to achieve in grade school it is virtually always the parents' fault.</title>
<source>http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/2qaf6l/cmv_if_a_child_struggles_to_achieve_in_grade/</source>
<OP author="unidangit">
<relation_support ref="a"> <logos> For the sake of this thread, we'll exclude children with medically diagnosed learning disabilities </logos> </relation_support>; <claim id="a"> IMO the knowledge and resource base for teaching said children is probably proportionate to the percentage they make up of the overall population </claim>.

<relation_support ref="b"> <logos> With a healthy child, income, neighborhood, peers and teachers should be filtered through a responsible parent(s). </logos> </relation_support> <claim id="b"> A child who struggles in earnest or intentionally slacks off is a direct reflection of parenting. </claim> <claim id="c"> I am curious regarding potential for more public accountability held to parents who fail to direct their child. </claim> (<relation_support ref="c"> <logos> maybe a monetary incentive derived from public tax coffers paid to parents of children who maintain a passing grade, to be withheld if child dips below </logos> </relation_support>.)

<claim id="d"> I think parents are virtually 100% responsible for producing scholastically successful children </claim>. CMV.
</OP>
<reply id="cn4b28t" author="hacksoncode">
  <claim id="e"> One of the largest predictors for success appears to be not being poor. </claim>

How would you account for that? <relation_undercutter ref="c"> <claim id="f"> It seems like fining poor people has some potential negative effects... on the children. </claim> </relation_undercutter>
</reply>
<reply id="cn4ckfy" author="unidangit">
  <relation_rebuttal_attack ref="f"> <claim id="g"> It wouldn't be a fine </claim> </relation_rebuttal_attack>, <relation_support ref="g"> <logos> since it would only be a suspension of "assistance" anyway </logos>. <logos> And poverty is a formidable obstacle but many, many people come from poverty to be wildly successful. </logos> </relation_support> <relation_rebuttal_attack ref="e"> <claim id="h"> That cannot be a blanket excuse for poor academic performance. </claim> </relation_rebuttal_attack> <claim id="i"> I believe the fulcrum of a child's development has always been, and will always be the parent(a living, mentally capable set of or just one parent). </claim>
</reply>
<reply id="cn4cvhm" author="hacksoncode">
<claim id="j"> Yeah </claim>, but <relation_undercutter ref="h"> <claim id="k"> my point is that giving money to people that have successful children is going, ultimately, to lead to giving money to people that already have money, and withholding it from ones that don't </claim> </relation_undercutter>. 

<relation_undercutter ref="h"> <claim id="l"> Unless you make the reward high enough to overcome the *reasons* that poor parents are less involved (<relation_support ref="l"> <logos> e.g. they don't have time because they are having to work 2 jobs just to support the children </logos> </relation_support>), it's not going to solve the problem. </claim> </relation_undercutter> And <claim id="m"> that's going to be very expensive </claim>. 

Furthermore, <claim id="n"> there's a more fundamental *reason* that poor parents are poorer at helping their children </claim>... <relation_support ref="n"> <logos> they're statistically dumber than richer people </logos>. <logos> Ignorance might be the cause, of course, rather than just lack of intrinsic intelligence </logos> </relation_support>. 

<claim id="o"> It would seem that a better approach would be to pay parents to attend training on how to be better parents, rather than rewarding the ones that have just happened to figure it out on their own </claim>. 

But honestly, <claim id="p"> I think you're just being naive about actual statistical variation in native intelligence </claim>. <relation_support ref="p"> <logos> There's really no reason to believe that every person has exactly the same potential to succeed well in school </logos>. <logos> A simpler explanation is that native intelligence is probably normally distributed, like almost every other trait people possess </logos> </relation_support>. 
</reply>
<reply id="cn4d9is" author="unidangit">
&amp;#8710;

Edit: tried to award you the delta. 

  <relation_agreement ref="p"> <claim id="q"> Native intelligence is the challenge. </claim> </relation_agreement> I won't delve into how this has infected my view, but <claim id="r"> I will say that it ties into why I think a moneyless society would over time revert to fiat currency </claim>. <relation_support ref="q"> <logos> Some people can do some thing's better than others </logos> </relation_support> ...thanks. <relation_agreement ref="p"> <claim id="s"> Nice exercise </claim> </relation_agreement>.

Edit: there we go!
</reply>
</thread>
